dugout.com 2017-09-02

# Dugout - Football Inside Out

This Privacy Policy explains the practices employed by Dugout Limited ('We', 'Us' or 'Dugout') in collecting and using your information and the ways in which you can influence these. This Privacy Policy relates to your use of Dugout through a device, in app form and through [www.dugout.com](http://www.dugout.com/) (' **Platform(s)** '). Unless separately defined herein, the defined terms in this Privacy Policy have the same meaning as in the Terms and Conditions which can be found on the Platform.

Dugout will collect various types of information about you through your use of the Platform to process your requests, to provide a more personalised user experience and to help us improve the services we offer. In doing this we may also collect anonymous information about you through the use of cookies and through other similar means. Dugout will be the Data Controller of any personal data we collect about you.

### 1\. What information do we collect about you?

By using the Platform, you can, amongst other things, follow your favourite clubs, players, legends and publishers, enter competitions, subscribe to any newsletters, complete surveys and place comments on articles and videos. 

In order for us to process your requests and activities, it may be necessary to collect personally identifiable information about you. The type of personally identifiable information that may be collected includes, but is not limited to: your name, address, e-mail address, location, age, gender and your preferences in relation to those clubs and players you choose to follow (' **Personal Information** '). 

In addition, we may collect anonymous information about you and your Platform usage through the use of cookies and through other similar means. Such information will not be personally identifiable to you. You may opt out of allowing our cookies to collect information about you. For further information please go to the cookies section below.

Our Platform may offer services that require you to set up an account prior to receiving such services. To create a secure account, you may use your email address and a password or, if the Platform offers a social media single-sign-on service, you will be able to register for and log in to your account by using your social media accounts such as Facebook, Twitter and Google.

If you choose to use sign-on using a social media platform service, we will gain access, upon your explicit consent, to your basic social media profile information prior to you completing the single-sign-on authorisation process.

### 2\. How will we use the information about you?

We may use the Personal Information you provide to us to communicate with you directly.

We will use the anonymous information we collect about you to analyse web usage and compile aggregate statistics about our users. We will use this non-personally identifiable information, for advertising and marketing purposes and to enable us to provide a more personalised Dugout experience for you. 

### 3\. Marketing

From time to time we will ask you whether you wish to receive marketing material from Dugout containing information about our services and partners. If you do not wish to receive such information, please ensure that you opt-in or opt-out of receiving such information as appropriate. If you have consented to receiving such material, you may opt-out at a later stage from emails by clicking on an email unsubscribe link or through the settings section of the Platform.

### 4\. What will we disclose to third parties?

We may provide anonymous, non-personally identifiable aggregate information to advertisers and to third parties, including information relating to, but not limited to, sales and web-usage, to enable us to sell advertising and monitor the efficacy of our relationships with third parties.

Further, under the terms of our individual agreements with clubs, players, publishers and legends (together known as ' **Publishers** ') featured on the Platform, we may be required to disclose your Personal Information to Publishers which you choose to follow on the Platform. Any such disclosure of your Personal Information shall be carried out in accordance with the applicable law of England and Wales. You acknowledge that by permitting the disclosure of your Personal Information by Dugout to those Publishers which you choose to follow on the Platform, those Publishers may contact you directly using the Personal Information provided to them, by Us.

It is possible that Dugout Limited could merge or be acquired by another business. If this happens we may share the information that relates to you with that other business. You will be sent notice of such an event. We reserve the right to disclose Personal Information in order to comply with the law, applicable regulations and government requests. We also reserve the right to use such information in order to protect our operating systems and integrity as well as other users.

Any third parties employed by us to process your data on our behalf are subject to contractual obligations to protect the security of your data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### 5\. How do we protect your information?

Once we have received your data we will ensure that it is treated with the utmost respect and privacy and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and any applicable regulations. Your data will be stored on our secure servers. We follow strict security procedures in order that the data we collect is stored and disclosed appropriately and securely. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will use reasonable endeavours to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to Us; any such transmission is at your own risk.

### 6\. Other Websites

Please note that clicking on links and advertisements on our Platform may result in your transferral to another website, where data privacy practices may vary to that of Dugout. If transferred to a third party site, you should consult the privacy policy of that other site as we are not responsible for and have no control over information that is submitted to or collected by any third party.

### 7\. Changes to our privacy policy

We will keep this privacy policy under review and may update it at any time. Any updates will be made on this page so that you can always find out what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we will disclose it.

### 8\. How to contact us

If you have any queries relating to our Privacy Policy please contact us by email to [info@dugout.com](mailto:info@dugout.com) or by writing to us: Dugout Limited, Medius House, 2 Sheraton Street, London, W1F 8BH.

## COOKIES

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that we, and in certain circumstances third parties, place on your browser when you visit our Platform or open some of our emails. Cookies, amongst other things, allow Us to recognise you each time you visit our Platform and provide you with a more personalised user experience. There are in existence a variety of different cookies which are designed for use in specific sets of circumstances.

### How do we and third parties use cookies?

You should be aware that information on you may be collected through the use of cookies when you use our Platform and/or selected third party sites. It is essential that we use cookies in order to provide you with the services you have requested from Us. Some cookies, however, whilst useful, are not essential, and when using the Platform, you agree to the use of these non-essential cookies unless you specifically set your browser to reject them. Please see 'How to manage or refuse cookies' below for further details.

When you initially enter our Platform, we may place an anonymous cookie on your browser to enable Us to recognise you the next time you use the Platform. We may also place a further cookie on your browser when you register for the Platform, this will enable us to remember you next time you come to sign in, eliminating the need for you to re-enter your login details and customising your future uses of our Platform.

Cookies may also be used to track your use of the Platform to better develop them, for example, determining which parts of the Platform are more popular and determining content accordingly.

We may also place cookies on your user device to provide you with behavioural advertising and monitor the advertising on the Platform to, amongst other things, ensure that you are not subjected to intrusive advertising.

Small pieces of code called pixel tags, web beacons or GIF files, are used in conjunction with cookies to help us manage and monitor our online advertising and wider business arrangements with third parties. These files will allow us to aggregate anonymous information relating to advertising and Platform usage. The type of information collected includes, but is not limited to, information relating to advertising responses, page views, promotion views and purchases made. Such pixel tags may be used to recognise third party cookies (cookies generated by third parties) and inform us and/or third parties of which advertisement or link brought you to our Platform, allowing us to monitor the efficacy of our business relationships with third parties. Please see the section below entitled 'Use of different cookies' for more detail on the various cookies in use by Us and how they work.

### How to manage or refuse cookies

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies and use them in the ways described above, it is possible to change your browser settings. It is also possible to delete existing cookies from your browser. However, blocking all cookies will affect your web experience and may result in some parts of the Platform not functioning properly. The procedure for modifying your privacy preferences is different for each internet browser and we recommend you visit the following websites for further information on altering your cookie settings:

For more detailed information on how to clear or disable all of your browser cookies, please go to [http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?answer=32050&hl=en](http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?answer=32050&hl=en)

#### Use of different cookies

We will use different cookies at various stages of your use of our Platform.

#### i) Tracking and Customisation Cookies

These are used to recognise repeat visitors to the Platform and customise the visitor experience, as described above. They may also be used in conjunction with other information we or our third party partners hold to attempt to record specific browsing information (for example, regarding the way visitors arrive at the Platform, pages viewed, options selected, information entered and the path taken through the Platform).

#### ii) Session Cookie

These are used to maintain your session when you sign into the Platform, allowing you to access the Platform's services without the need to sign in on every page you visit. The session cookie is used to tailor advertising to you on the Platform and selected third party websites. If you opt out of tailored advertising, we stop using this cookie for this purpose.

#### iii) Advertising Cookies

Dugout works with third parties for the purpose of delivering targeted behavioural advertising to the Platform. Through the use of cookies, anonymous information about your use of our Platform and other websites will be used to provide more relevant adverts about goods and services of interest to you. Specific cookies used by Dugout in relation to behavioural advertising include:

#### iv) Cookies placed independently by third parties

The majority of the adverts you see on the Platform will have been placed by third parties. These third parties may choose to generate their own cookies for the purposes of collecting anonymous information relating to the viewing of their advertising. The information collected cannot be used to personally identify someone. You can find out more about this method of advertising by visiting these sites: 

    <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/about.html>
    <http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy/>
    <http://www.pubmatic.com/privacy-policy.php>
    <http://openx.com/legal/privacypolicy/>
    <http://privacy.aol.co.uk/privacy-policy/>
    <https://www.spotxchange.com/privacy-policy/>
    <https://sticky.ai/privacy-policy/>
    <http://www.tremorvideo.com/en/privacy-policy>
    <https://platform-cdn.sharethrough.com/privacy-policy>

© Dugout Limited (February, 2017)
